{
    "question": "Terdiri dari apa sajakah causative have itu",
    "attachments": [],
    "answers": [
        {
            "answer": "Causative verb menunjukkan bahwa seseorang/sesuatu secara tidak langsung bertanggung jawab terhadap sebuah tindakan. Subjek tidak melakukan tindakan itu sendiri, tetapi justru menyebabkan seseorang/sesuatu yang lain melakukannya. Contoh:<br>- Yesterday I had my hair cut.<br>Pembicara pada kalimat diatas tidak memotong sendiri rambutnya, tetapi justru membuat orang lain melakukannya \u2013 Saya \u201cmenyebabkan\u201d mereka memotong rambut saya.<br>Have<br>Have merupakan causative verb yang umum. Ketimbang melakukan sesuatu dengan diri kita sendiri, kita \u201cmenyuruh\u201d orang yang lain untuk melakukannya. Bentuknya sebagai berikut:<br>Kata kerja \u201cto have\u201d + objek + past participle (verb 3). Contoh:<br>- I had my jacket cleaned yesterday.<br>- Did you have your computer fixed?<br>Terkadang kita menggunakan have sebagai causative verb ketika kita ingin melakukan tindakan oleh diri kita sendiri. Contoh:<br>- When will the report be ready? I\u2019ll do it by tomorrow morning. &gt;&gt;<br>- When will the report be ready? I\u2019ll have it done by tomorrow morning.<br>Dengan menggunakan causative, kalimat ke-dua diatas mengalihkan perhatian dari pelaku tindakan, dan lebih memberikan perhatian kepada tindakan yang sedang dilakukan. Ini kedengaran sopan dan profesional.<br>Get<br>Get sering digunakan ketimbang have. Contoh:<br>\u2022\tI got my computer fixed \u2013 I had my computer fixed. Kedua kalimat ini maknanya sama.<br>\u2022\tI got my jacket cleaned. \u2013 I had my jacket cleaned. Kedua kalimat ini maknanya sama.<br>Causative verbs sering digunakan bersama dengan pengalaman-pengalaman negatif. Pada situasi-situasi ini lebih umum menggunakan have. Contoh:<br>\u2022\tI had my wallet stolen. (Saya sebenarnya tidak menyebabkan dompet saya dicuri \u2013 seseorang mencuri dompet saya dariku)<br><span>\u2022\tShe had her window smashed.<br><br></span>",
            "attachments": []
        }
    ],
    "related_questions": [
        {
            "slug": "1-the-word-darling-is-derived-from-an-old-english-term-meaning-251",
            "question": "1. The word \"Darling\" is derived from an old english term meaning \"Favorite Minion\" . Explain the positive and negative meaning of \"Darling\".    2. IBM is has laid of 20 percent of their workforce with a signature on a single piece of paper.\r\n\u00a0\u00a0 \u00a0 1\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0\u00a0 2\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0\u00a0 3\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0\u00a0 \u00a0 4\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 5\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0\u00a0 6\r\na. Find out the error option.\r\nb. Explain why it is wrong\r\n\r\nmohon bantuannya yaa..",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "1. The word \"Darling\" is derived from an old English term meaning \"Favorite Minion\" . Explain the positive and negative meaning of \"Darling\".<br>Positive Meaning : It&#039;s a person that we concern as lovely and lovable, therefore we prioritize this darling as the first priority.<br>Negative : Since the word darling means favorite minion, it also trigger the feeling of possessiveness, that sometime it has negative effect on their freedom and privacy.\u00a0<br><br><span>2.\u00a0</span><u>IBM</u><span>\u00a0is\u00a0</span><u>has</u><span>\u00a0laid of\u00a0</span><u>20 percent</u><span>\u00a0of\u00a0</span><u>their</u>\u00a0<u>workforce</u><span>\u00a0with a signature on a\u00a0</span><u>single</u><span>\u00a0piece of paper.</span><br>\u00a0\u00a0 \u00a0 1\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0\u00a0 2\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0\u00a0 3\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0\u00a0 \u00a0 4\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 5\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0\u00a0 6<br>a. Find out the error option.<br><br>number 2 - &gt; should be<br>IBM has laid without &#039;is&#039;\u00a0<br>b. Explain why it is wrong<br>if we use Is, then it will have pasive meaning, which means that IBM get bankrupt due to their worker\u00a0<br><br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "berikan-5-kalimat-giving-instruction-312",
            "question": "Berikan 5 kalimat giving instruction",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "aku tulis dalam procedural text, how to make omelete<br>first,crack the eggs<br>after that beat the eggs<br>an then mix it with a salt or meat<br>after that cook it in a hot plate<br>finaly eat the eggs",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "apa-beda-auxilary-amp-operator-siapa-penemu-font-old-english-907",
            "question": "-Apa beda Auxilary &amp; Operator?    -Siapa penemu font Old English?\r\n -Kapan Bahasa Inggris masuk ke Indonesia?",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "gaktau ee kak bntar takcarikan yha<br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "tolong-jelaskan-secara-singkat-dan-jelas-pengertian-dari-report-t-269",
            "question": "Tolong jelaskan secara singkat dan jelas pengertian dari report teks",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "Definition of Report<br>Report is a text which presents information about something, as it is. It is as a result of systematic observation and analysis<br><br>Generic Structure of Report<br>1. General classification: Stating classification of general aspect of thing; animal, public place, plant, etc which will be discussed in general<br>2. Description: Describing the thing which will be discussed in detail; part per part , customs or deed for living creature and usage for materials<br><br>Language Feature of Report<br>\u2022 Introducing group or general aspect<br>\u2022 Using conditional logical connection; when, so, etc<br><span>\u2022 Using simple present tense</span>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "report text adalah salah satu jenis teks yang masuk kategori \" factual text \"<br><br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "lanjutan-jawaban-dari-in-the-developed-world-where-more-than-70-898",
            "question": "Lanjutan jawaban dari \"in the developed world, where more than 70% of citizens already live in cities, urbanization is spread evenly, and population growth\" pilihan nya    a. has slowed\r\nb. would slow\r\nc. slowed\r\nd. had slowed\r\ne. will slow\r\n(simple future tense)",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "d. in the developed world, where more than 70% of citizens al already live in cities. urbanization is spread evenly. and population growth <u>had slowed</u>. <br>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "bisa saja isinya yang\u00a0<br>b. would slow, karena future pasti akan menggunakan will dan would adalah bentuk kedua dari modals tsb",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "buat-kalimat-pujian-responnya-tentang-memuji-keindahan-alam-me-798",
            "question": "buat kalimat pujian + responnya tentang memuji keindahan alam, memuji mother, father, granpa/ma, teacher, brother and sister, friend, best friend pet, your self",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "1. Keindahan alam :<br>A: Wow! such a beautiful park.<br>B: Yea! i think so.<br><br>2. Teacher :<br>A: Thanks Miss jasmine! i understand it well than before.<br>B: Your welcome.<br><br>Semoga membantu :D",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "Alam <br>A : Look at that beautiful lake !<br>B : Amazing<br>Mother<br>A : mom, you look pretty everytime !<br>B : thank you dear<br>Father\u00a0<br>A : Dad, you cook this ?<br>B : Yup.<br>A : waw, you can be a great chef<br>Grandpa<br>A: Grandpa, do you made this toys ?<br>B : yes, my dear<br>A : its look amazing !<br>Brother<br>A : Hey, you made this story ?<br>B: yup<br>A : Its so funny ! i love it<br>Teacher\u00a0<br>A : Sir, I never met a great teacher like you<br>B : thank you<br>friend :<br>A : Hey, you look pretty when you wear that dress<br>B : really ? thank you !<br>Best friend per<br>A : your cat is so cute.<br>B: Hahaha, yes, i know that<br>Yourself :<br>A : Hey, i look beautifull with this t-shirt !",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "apa-keegunaan-dari-whowhosewhomwhichwhere-dalam-adjective-cla-586",
            "question": "apa keegunaan dari who,whose,whom,which,where dalam adjective clause, saya agak kurang mengerti sepenuhnya ?",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "Who\u00a0=\u00a0( Sentences + Adjective Clause + Auxilary/Verb\u00a0) Untuk Subject<br>\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0Ex:\u00a0<strong>I saw the man <u>who is </u>tall<br>\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0Is =</strong> Auxilary<br><br>Whom =\u00a0( Sentences + Adjective Clause + Subject ) Untuk Subject<u><br></u> \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 Ex:\u00a0<strong>The woman <u>whom you</u> saw last night is my sister<br></strong>\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0<strong>You =\u00a0</strong>Subject<br><br>Whose = ( Sentences + Adjective Clause + Noun ) Untuk Subject<br>\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0Ex:\u00a0<strong>Santi <u>whose hair</u> is black and lock is beautiful<br></strong><strong>\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0Hair =\u00a0</strong>Noun<br><br>Which = ( Sentences + Adjective Clause + Aux/S/Verb ) Untuk Object<br>\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0Ex:\u00a0<strong>The food <u>which is</u> made of bread and sausage is hot dog<br>\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0The cat <u>which sultan</u> feeds every morning is very funny<br>\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0Is =\u00a0</strong>Auxilary<br>\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0\u00a0<strong> Sultan =\u00a0</strong>Subject<br><br>Where = Untuk menjelaskan tempat<br>\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0Ex:\u00a0<strong>Mall, where we shopping is aweso</strong><strong>me<br></strong><strong><br></strong>Semoga bermanfaat :)\u00a0<br><strong></strong>Jika ingin bertanya, silahkan komen dibawah :)<br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "tolong-berikan-contoh-dialogue-4-orang-yang-didalam-dialogue-ters-769",
            "question": "tolong berikan contoh dialogue 4 orang yang didalam dialogue tersebut terdapat expressing love ,expressing\u00a0sadness ,expressing\u00a0embarrassment ,expressing attitudes towards something and ,expressing\u00a0anger snd annoyance.",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "A: i love you<br>B: i love you too but i can&#039;t to be with you. i&#039;m sorry",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "bahasa-inggris-nya-dikejar-190",
            "question": "Bahasa inggris nya dikejar?? ...",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<strong><em>be pursued<br><br>jadiin yang terbaik yah kakak</em></strong>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "klu nggasalah <br><span>chased</span><br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "soal-all-these-year-dinas-family-in-poverty-a-has-485",
            "question": "Soal : all these year , Dina's family.......... in poverty    a. has lived\u00a0\r\nb. was living\u00a0\r\nc. lives\u00a0\r\nd. has been living\r\ne. lived\u00a0\r\n\r\ntolong sertai dengan penjelasan ya",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "yang bener jawaban D kalo menurutku. Itu termasuk kalimat Present Perfect Continuous Tense yang rumusnya S + have/has + been + Ving. Tujuan teks itu adalah untuk menyatakan suatu kegiatan yang dimulai pada waktu lampau tetapi masih berlangsung sampai sekarang bahkan ada kemungkinan akan terus berlangsung. Clue nya itu phrase \"All these years\"<br><br>menurutku sih begitu\u00a0",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}